floridabar.org 2019-10-11

# The Florida Bar Privacy Policy – The Florida Bar

## **THE FLORIDA BAR   –** **Privacy Policy**

Thank you for visiting The Florida Bar. Our goal in offering the site for member use is simple – to provide interested members with a secure environment in which they may conduct secure online transactions with The Florida Bar and its systems. Whether that activity is Fee Payment, Address Change, or CLE Registration, we are committed to providing convenient, high quality services to our members. In order to accomplish that goal, certain user data may be collected and/or reviewed so that we can understand all Members Portal activity and, in turn, make the site all the more relevant to our members.

We are mindful of the concerns that some members may have regarding the privacy implications of the site, and therefore provide the information below so that users may have a better understanding of the information collected, its ultimate use, Bar systems and procedures, and other issues that may influence access to member data.

## **Information Collected and its Use**

Information collected from **both Members and the public** includes:

_Server log information_ : When you visit the Members Portal or any other website, your PC is identified by a unique number called an IP address. Your IP address is automatically collected in server logs. Website administrators use this information to help diagnose problems with our server and to analyze server traffic to assess use volume and gauge the popularity of particular site pages. This information cannot be traced back to a specific individual. The server log also can tell us which browser you are using (i.e. Internet Explorer or Netscape), and the name of the website that referred you to our site. (i.e., if you were visiting Lexis.com and clicked on a link to the Members Portal, you were “referred” through Lexis.com).

_Cookies_ : These are text files that our website and many others place on your computer’s hard drive to keep track of your preferences. We may use cookies to personalize your experience on the Members Portal, i.e. cookies may help us remember that you regularly purchase CLE products related to family law, so that we might advise you of other related Bar products or services based on those known preferences.

Information collected from **Members only** includes:

_User-supplied information_ : Court rules already require that members regularly advise the Bar of basic personal information such as name, address, and business telephone number. Many members voluntarily supplement their membership profile with fax numbers and email addresses as well, although this is not required.

Use of the Bar Members Portal particularly activities involving purchase or payment, requires that you give us limited personal information to confirm your identity.

Members should be aware that the Florida Constitution and Supreme Court rules make most member information received in connection with the transaction of official business of the Bar a “record” with few exemptions from public access. Art. 1, Sec. 24, Fla. Const.; Fla.R.Jud.Admin. 2.051; R.RegulatingFla.Bar 1-14.1; In Re Amendments to Fla. Rules, 608 So.2d 472 (Fla. 1992).

Member credit card account numbers used in connection with the Members Portal are protected and exempt from public disclosure.

However, by providing the necessary information for any Members Portal transaction, you can and will be able to conduct certain Bar business via the Internet which in the past required telephone or mail contact with our headquarters offices. These online services are provided as a convenience to our members, but are not their only option. Members are still free to use traditional “paper” methods for Fee Payment, CLE Registration, and the like.

## **Adjust or Correct Your Information**

To protect your privacy and the security of your membership data, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections to any member record. Members may access and/or adjust their individual membership profile by following these steps:

  1. Using your browser, go to <https://www.floridabar.org/> and select LOGIN or go to [https://member.floridabar.org ](https://member.floridabar.org/)
  2. Enter your Username and Password. Select the **Login** button.
  3. On the next screen, to the right of “My Profile” select the “Update” link.
  4. Change information appears as entered.
  5. When changes are complete, select  **Save Profile Information**.
  6. Your membership profile is now updated with this information. Note that, if your address information cannot be validated by our postal software, the membership profile will not be immediately updated. A member of our Membership Records staff will manually update the information following manual validation.

The Bar uses this procedure to better safeguard your basic membership information. Members are encouraged to correct factual errors in their listings and/or update changed information as soon as possible in order to maintain their access to the Members Portal. Basic membership data that the Bar is required to maintain by court rule may not be deleted, and public access to it cannot be denied.

Contact Membership Records staff with other questions regarding your record:

The Florida Bar  
Membership Records  
651 E. Jefferson St.  
Tallahassee, Florida 32399-2300  
850/561-5832

## **Security & Credit Card Transactions**

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of collected information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. Currently, members may use Visa or MasterCard when transacting business such as CLE Registration or Fee Payment using the Members Portal.

Again, state law recognizes that Members Portal passwords in the possession of the Bar _are_ confidential. §119.07(6)(o), Fla.Stat.

Credit card account numbers are similarly protected. §119.07(6)(dd), Fla.Stat.

Member credit card details are maintained only to the extent that such maintenance is required to complete the current transaction, and these details are not stored beyond the current transaction. Credit card information is not shared with third parties unrelated to the credit card approval process.

In those instances where credit card details are provided, The Florida Bar specifically uses the industry standard encryption software, Secured Sockets Layer (SSL). This technology protects your information from unauthorized use via advanced encryption technology and is used by numerous retailers on the Internet to protect confidential credit card and transactional information (for a more technical definition, visit <http://searchsecurity.techtarget.com/sDefinition/0,,sid14_gci343029,00.html>). The URL in your browser will change to “HTTPS” instead of “HTTP” when this security feature is invoked, and your browser may also display a lock symbol on its bottom task bar line to indicate invoked secure transmission (note that some browsers or “framed” websites may not show this lock symbol).

## **Third Parties**

Our Website contains links to other websites operated by third parties. The Florida Bar is not responsible for the privacy practices or policies of such third party websites and this Notice does not apply to those websites.

## **Contact Us with Questions**

If you have any questions about The Florida Bar privacy policy or its effect on your ability to use the Members Portal with confidence, you may:

_Write:_

**Privacy Officer**

**Office of the General Counsel  
The Florida Bar** **  
651 E. Jefferson St** **.  
Tallahassee, Florida 32399-2300**

_Call or Email:_

**Office of the General Counsel**

(850) 561-5661 _  
_[privacy@floridabar.org](mailto:privacy@floridabar.org)

**Future Changes to the Privacy Policy**

If the practices or policies of The Florida Bar described in these statements materially change, such changes will be reflected in a revised privacy statement.
